New Directions Publishing Corp. New Directions catalogs, circulars and printed ephemera, 1936-(ongoing) (MS Am 2077.3): Guide.
New Directions catalogs, circulars, and printed ephemera,
1936-(ongoing).
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 2077.3
New Directions Publishing Corp.
7 boxes (2 linear ft.)
Sales catalogs, circulars, and other printed materials from the New Directions Publishing Corporation founded by publisher-poet James Laughlin in 1936.
*97M-49. Bequest of James Laughlin IV, 1997; received: 1998 April 30.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material.
Arranged chronologically.
Collection includes: advertisements, book order postcards, sales catalogs, circular letters, clippings, newsletters (including "News from New Directions"), posters, press releases, etc. There are a few manuscript drafts of text for some of these printed materials, some written by James Laughlin, and also information concerning the history of the corporation.
This collection will be added to as new materials are produced by NDPC.
- Poster, undated., (1); 1 folder.
  Red, white and black poster designed by Lustig (noted in top right corner). Titled, "New Directions Books."
- 1936., (2); 1 folder.
  Folder includes the "first list [for ND publications] a sort of handbill on cheap yellow paper announcing the first anthology, which was printed at the shop of the Country newspaper in Canaan, Conn." [Note by JL, see folder for 1937 below.
- 1937., (3); 1 folder.
  Includes AMs notes by JL concerning the history of ND catalogs and indicating that the "second general list issued by ND, probably early in 1937, was printed by Samuel Marcus in Cambridge. There were three variant texts of the long statement of policy, one slanted for 'The Reader', one for 'The Librarian' and one for the 'Bookseller.' All of the books listed were actually published except I The Eye, which bogged down in complicated layout plans involving a format measuring 3x12 inches, a requirement a little puzzling to the printers approached, and was never carried through."
- 1938., (4); 1 folder.
- 1939., (5); 2 folders.
- 1940., (6); 2 folders.
- 1941., (7); 2 folders.
- 1942., (8); 1 folder.
- 1943., (9); 1 folder.
- 1944., (10); 1 folder.
- 1945., (11); 1 folder.
- 1946., (12); 1 folder.
- 1947., (13); 1 folder.
- 1948., (14); 1 folder.
- 1949., (15); 1 folder.
- 1950., (16); 1 folder.
- 1951., (17); 1 folder.
- 1952., (18); 1 folder.
- 1953., (19); 1 folder.
- 1954., (20); 2 folders.
- 1955., (21); 1 folder.
- 1956., (22); 1 folder.
- 1957., (23); 1 folder.
- 1958., (24); 1 folder.
- 1959., (25); 1 folder.
- 1960., (26); 1 folder.
- 1961., (27); 1 folder.
- 1962., (28); 2 folders.
- 1963., (29); 1 folder.
- 1964., (30); 1 folder.
- 1965., (31); 1 folder.
- 1966., (32); 1 folder.
- 1967., (33); 1 folder.
- 1968., (34); 1 folder.
- 1969., (35); 1 folder.
- 1970., (36); 1 folder.
- 1971., (37); 1 folder.
- 1972., (38); 2 folders.
- 1973., (39); 1 folder.
- 1974., (40); 2 folders.
- 1975., (41); 1 folder.
- 1976., (42); 1 folder.
- 1977., (43); 1 folder.
- 1978., (44); 1 folder.
- 1979., (45); 1 folder.
- 1980., (46); 1 folder.
- 1981., (47); 1 folder.
- 1982., (48); 1 folder.
- 1983., (49); 1 folder.
- 1984., (50); 1 folder.
- 1985., (51); 1 folder.
- 1986., (52); 1 folder.
- 1987., (53); 1 folder.
- 1988., (54); 2 folders.
- 1989., (55); 1 folder.
- 1990., (56); 1 folder.
- 1991., (57); 2 folders.
- 1992., (58); 2 folders.
- 1993., (59); 1 folder.
- 1994., (60); 1 folder.
- 1995., (61); 1 folder.
- 1996., (62); 1 folder.
- 1997., (63); 1 folder.
- 1998., (64); 1 folder.
- 1999., (65); 1 folder.
- 2000., (66); 1 folder.
- 2001., (67); 1 folder.
- Undated., (68); 1 folder.
- News from New Directions, 1939-(ongoing)., (69); 20 folders.
  Ongoing series of newsletter.
- 2005., (70); 1 folder.
- 2006., (71); 1 folder.
- 2007., (72); 1 folder.
- 2008., (73); 1 folder.
- 2010., (74); 1 folder.
- 2011., (75); 1 folder.